<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflexión on Call me Guido</title>
    <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/categories/reflexi%C3%B3n/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflexión on Call me Guido</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 14:04:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://guidogarcia.net/blog/categories/reflexi%C3%B3n/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mi experiencia HackForGood 2015</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2015/06/16/mi-experiencia-hackforgood-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2015/06/16/mi-experiencia-hackforgood-2015/</guid>
      <description>HackForGood es un hackaton centrado en la innovación social, donde se desarrollan de forma colaborativa nuevas ideas que ayuden a resolver problemas sociales. Los días 16-18 de abril sacrificamos un día de vacaciones para pasarnos por la tercera edición de la iniciativa HackForGood en la Universidad de Valladolid.
Nuestro equipo &amp;ldquo;Senior OS&amp;rdquo; iba con la idea de hacer un teléfono móvil para personas mayores, sin ningún tipo de configuración y que se pudiese gestionar íntegramente de forma remota.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The long tail in this blog</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2014/01/23/the-long-tail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2014/01/23/the-long-tail/</guid>
      <description>This blog is two years old, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share how its &amp;gt;50K visits are distributed.

One single post drives 40% of the traffic to the blog. At the bottom, 70% of its posts represent 4% of the traffic.
In my opinion, the most popular ones are not the best ones. They are about very specific technical subjects, containing keywords in the title and in the URL slug. Google does the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big teams are not agile in the digital world</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2013/08/12/big-teams-are-not-agile-in-the-digital-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 14:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2013/08/12/big-teams-are-not-agile-in-the-digital-world/</guid>
      <description>The post today is not so technical. I have been thinking about why many big corporations, with almost unlimited resources, are not able to deliver top quality products and services. Why companies with a small fraction of resources create new products faster?
I have found several sociopsychological causes, most of them related with an aspect of human activity: working in a team.
Diffusion of responsibility Diffusion of responsibility is a sociopsychological phenomenon whereby a person is less likely to take responsibility for action or inaction when others are present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inauguro el blog</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2011/07/14/inauguracion-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 15:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2011/07/14/inauguracion-blog/</guid>
      <description>Con varios años de retraso inauguro el blog en el que ire recogiendo mis reflexiones relacionadas con el mundo en general y la tecnología en particular. Aprovecharé para recoger lo que tenía desperdigado por la red.
Os animo a suscribiros, a participar en los comentarios y a que me enviéis vuestras sugerencias y críticas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>