<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Call me Guido</title>
    <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Call me Guido</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 16:19:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://guidogarcia.net/blog/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to catch an Internet troll</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2014/04/25/how-to-catch-an-internet-troll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 16:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2014/04/25/how-to-catch-an-internet-troll/</guid>
      <description>Some weeks ago I carried out a social experiment (dameunverso.com, spanish) that consisted in writing a poem in a collaborative and anonymous way. This means that anyone can add a new verse to the poem without identifying themselves or leaving any metadata (no cookies, no IP address tracking, etc).
Our first trolls didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to appear, mostly in the form of copyrighted material, spam and offensive contents. Is it possible to automatically classify an anonymous verse as spammy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of variance (ANOVA) applied to fraud detection</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2012/08/26/analysis-of-variance-anova-applied-to-fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 17:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2012/08/26/analysis-of-variance-anova-applied-to-fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>Fraud detection is a topic applicable to many sectors (financial, insurance, etc). The method explained in this post is applied in the market research field by Gather Precision (a great market research tool developed by Gather Estudios, BTW), as an early signal to detect frauds in opinion polls.
Imagine you have four field workers (Peter, John, Mary, Ann) taking surveys on the street. They spend different times gathering the data, and we want to discover if there are significant differences on the average levels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>