<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Call me Guido</title>
    <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Call me Guido</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:56:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://guidogarcia.net/blog/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud is not cheap</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2014/03/18/cloud-is-not-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 06:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2014/03/18/cloud-is-not-cheap/</guid>
      <description>There is a myth about cloud computing. Many people think they will save money moving their services to the cloud, but the reality is that the cloud is not cheap.
Virtualization, one of the core parts of cloud computing, tries to meet the promise of elastic capacity and pay-as-you-go policies. Despite of this promise, the true story is that today we are running virtual machines that don&amp;rsquo;t do much because, most part of the time, our applications are not doing anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy virtual machines on Instant Servers cloud with Java</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2013/02/17/deploy-virtual-machines-on-instant-servers-cloud-with-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2013/02/17/deploy-virtual-machines-on-instant-servers-cloud-with-java/</guid>
      <description>Instant Servers is the infrastructure as a service (IaaS) system I have been working on during the last months in Telefónica Digital.
The service offers a public REST API (Cloud API) that is super simple to use. However, in this post I will show you how to manage your infrastructure using a Java client, without dealing with HTTP requests.
Build the Cloud API client Man does not live by nodejs alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google App Engine: Disturbances in the Force</title>
      <link>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2011/09/08/google-app-engine-new-pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 22:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://guidogarcia.net/blog/blog/2011/09/08/google-app-engine-new-pricing/</guid>
      <description>A New Hope. The pay as you go promise. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Google App Engine (GAE) since it first appeared back in 2008. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know what am I talking about, GAE is a Platform as a Service (PaaS) cloud computing platform provided by Google where you can deploy your Python, Java and Go web applications.
You only have to deploy your application (using a very simple toolkit) and Google takes care of launching new application instances when necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>